Akash Patel

Web Developer

A creative professional with 3 years of hands on for web & mobile application. I am a multi-tasking web designer with passion for designing clean and functional websites, web applications & development along with print media. I amWeb developer with experience coding websites and web application using Javascript, React, Angular, NPM, NodeJS, HTML, CSS, wordPress, javascript, jquary, Bootstrap. I focus on writing clear and efficient codes. Pixel perfect creation & attention to details are my strengths and I believe in quality oriented results. Currently residing in Scarborough, ON, Canada. I am looking to grow professionally and personally

designndevbyakash@gmail.com

6476077560

28 Armada Ct, Toronto, Canada

in linkedin.com/in/akash-patel-98885a182

WORK EXPERIENCE

Web Production Artist

TVO - Sep 2019 - Present

- Developing and maintaining automation scripts which can optimize production work.
- Developing and maintaining reusable Interactive Learning Objects and widgets for students.
- Producing vendor files for all course using NPM, Node.js, Webpack, Grunt and Gulp bundling tools
- Troubleshooting the bugs reported by internal QA team or external team. Finding solution globally which can improve AODA of course project.
- Responsible for taking care of W3C and WCAG 2.0 (Level AA) and AODA Compliance.
- Improving web accessibility of courses and developed scripts to automate some of the work.

Web Developer

Taggut Production - Jun 2020 - Dec 2020

- Design customized theme using WordPress.
- Design customized theme for Shopify. Shopify code edit expert.
- Developing Game using HTML5 Canvas, CSS, JavaScript and jQuery.
- Responsible for testing website, Forms included in the website, login splash screen etc.
- Following Designer's Guideline to Develop responsive website.
- Design of great visual identity that are SEO Friendly.
- Proficiency in Creative Design Software specifically Photoshop, Illustrator and wire-framing tools
- PSD to HTML exporting and maintaining all W3C standards.
- Hands on experience Design Brochure, Logo, Poster, Roll Up Banner, Business Card

Front-end developer

Boldpod inc - Jan 2019 - Sep 2019

- Design customized theme using WordPress
- Develop an app using phone gap for Android OS and IOS.
- Design of great visual identity that are SEO Friendly.
- PSD to HTML exporting and maintaining all W3C standards.
- Maintaining AODA and W3C standard in all website developed.
- Responsible for testing website, Forms included in the website, login splash screen etc.
- Design professional PPT, Mockups, Blog graphics, Infographics, as well as poster design
- Proficiency in Creative Design Software specifically Photoshop, Illustrator and wire-framing tools

STACK OF TECHNOLOGIES

- HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Material UI, Tailwind, Less and Sass
- JavaScript, jQuery,Node.JS, Python, Vue, React, PHP, Ruby on rails
- CMS: Wordpress, Adobe Experience Manager, Shopify
- Visual Studio Code, git Version Control, MySQL, Postgres, MongoDB
- Gulp, Grunt, Webpack
- Linux, Windows, Mac

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Application Gujarat University - Jun 2014 - May 2016

Javascript and AngularJS

Seneca college - Apr 2019 - Aug 2019

LANGUAGES

- English Full Professional Proficiency
- Gujarati Full Professional Proficiency
- Hindi Full Professional Proficiency
- Punjabi Communication Proficiency
- Urdu Communication Proficiency